Guide to the Triad Club Records 1925-1999
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
Triad Club Records
1925-1999
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center University Archives 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://osulibrary.oregonstate.edu/archives
MSS Triad Club
Triad Club (Oregon State University)
1.3 cubic feet 4 boxes
The Triad Club Records document the activities and operation of this organization of Oregon State University faculty established in 1926 to further "fellowship, cooperation, and service" among faculty, students, and the citizens of Corvallis. The records include membership lists, minutes, scrapbooks, photographs, and anniversary publications.
Historical Note:
The Triad Club was organized in 1926 by School of Commerce faculty member A. C. Schmitt. Initially open only to male faculty members with two or more years of service at OSU, the club was established to further "fellowship, cooperation, and service" among the different depart-ments of the University, the students, and the citizens of Corvallis. Holding weekly luncheon meetings where members and guest speakers offer programs and presentations, the club selects members through a membership committee. Reversing their original charter, the club began to admit women in 1978 with Lois McGill selected as the first female member.
Series I contains materials relating to club membership and includes lists of members organized by year, chronologically, and alphabetically; and lists of officers and committee members. Records relating to meeting attendance and membership information forms compiled for the 30th anniversary of the club are included in this series. The information forms contain biographical data such as work histories, education, etc. Series II consists of meeting minutes. Series III is primarily correspondence and pertains to meeting attendance, remembrance of deceased members, committees, budgetary expenditures, topics of weekly meetings, and the Oregon State College Masonic student organization the Square and Compass Club. Series IV contains publications published for the Triad Club membership and includes booklets commemorating the club's 30th and 50th anniversaries, the club Songbook, and printed quotations and invocations by club chaplain and member Delmer Goode.
Series V consists of copies of the club's constitutions and bylaws, as well as revisions and amendments to the original charter. Series VI consists of newspaper clippings from The Oregon Journal and The Corvallis Gazette-Times on the activities and deaths of Triad Club members, the history of OSU, and the Square and Compass Club. Series VII is a scrapbook with newspaper clippings on Triad club events and members, Christmas cards, thank you notes, and correspondence. Materials date from 1926 to 1940. Series VIII contains photographs of club members in group shots, monthly meetings, and holiday parties. Series IX is an audiotape recording and two scripts of a speech delivered by Ken Munford for the 60th Anniversary celebration. Series X consists of two artifacts: the old gavel used to open club meetings and a charter member ribbon prepared for the 30th Anniversary celebration.
The records of the Triad Club are organized into 10 series: I. Membership Lists and Information; II. Minutes; III. Correspondence; IV. Publications; V. Constitutions and Bylaws; VI. Newspaper Clipping; VII. Scrapbooks; VIII. Photographs; IX. Sound Recordings; and X. Artifacts.
Collection is open for research.
Documentation pertaining to the Triad Club can also be found in the records of several OSU Departments and offices, including Crop Science (RG 95), Mathematics (RG 136), and Landscape Architecture(RG 89). The papers of former Triad President Paul Bernier also contain materials relating to the club. There are photographs of Triad Club activities and members in a variety of collections, including the Robert W. Henderson Photographs (P 98).
Munford, James Kenneth.; Goode, Delmer M.; Munford, James Kenneth.; Goode, Delmer M.
Triad Club (Oregon State University); Square and Compass Club (Oregon State College); Oregon State University--Faculty.
Clubs--Oregon--Corvallis.; Grace at meals.
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
City and Town Life; Colleges and Universities; Corvallis; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Sound Recordings; Artifacts
- Membership Lists and Information, 1926-1999; Series I
  - Committee Lists, 1926-1987/1988 (Box 1)
  - List of Deceased Members, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Lists of Triad Club Officers, 1926-1999 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Attendance Rosters, 1933-1947 (Box 1)
  - Membership Lists By Year, 1926/1927-1998/1999 (Box 1)
  - Membership Lists Organized Alphabetically and Chronologically, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Membership Selection Actions, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Triad (Membership) Information Sheets, 1956-1966 (Box 1)
- Minutes, 1925-1979; Series II
  - 1925-1952 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - 1958-1972 (Box 1)
  - 1979 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1925-1999; Series III
  - Budgetary, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
  - Delmer Goode-Heatherhold Christmas Newsletters, 1970-1977 (Box 1)
  - General, 1926-1934, 1943-1965, 1972-1999 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Committee, undated (Box 1)
  - Membership Committee, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Notices, 1977-1979, 1987-1999 (Box 1)
  - Program Committee, 1945-1979 (Box 1)
  - Square and Compass Club, 1925-1947 (Box 1)
- Publications, 1945-circa 1988; Series IV
  - Corvallis Magazine, Winter, 1964 (Box 1)
    (Quarterly brochure on the history of Benton County published by local businessman Thomas A. Wilson. Group photo of Triad Club for 30th Anniversary is featured)
  - Thirtieth Anniversary Booklet, 1956 (Box 1)
    (Pamphlet produced in conjunction with 30th Anniversary of the club, 3 copies)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Booklet, 1976; 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Graces, circa 1988 (Box 1)
    (A booklet of printed invocations originally delivered at club meetings by Chaplain Delmer Goode, 4 copies)
  - Graces, 1986 (Box 1)
    (Publication drafts of Graces-includes list of invocations not used in final printed booklet)
  - Professor's Notebook Leaflets, 1945-1946 (Box 1)
    (Flyers with quotes on the history and mission of higher education. Assembled by Delmer Goode and distributed at club meetings.)
  - Triad Songbook, undated (Box 1)
- Constitutions/Bylaws, 1934-1997; Series V (Box 1)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1941-1996; Series VI (Box 2)
- Scrapbooks, 1940; Series VII (Box 2)
  (including photocopied reference copy)
- Photographs, 1931-1978; Series VIII
  - Group Shots, 1931-1976 (Box 3)
  - Meetings/Events, 1964-1978 (Box 3)
  - Photographs Used in 50th Anniversary Booklet, 1976 (Box 3)
- Sound Recordings, 1986; Series IX
  - Speech: 60th Anniversary Meeting, 5/29/86 (Two copies of the script are included with the tape) (Box 4)
- Artifacts, circa 1926-1956; Series X
  - Triad Club Gavel, circa 1926 (Box 2)
    (Used prior to presentation of gavel by President A. L. Strand)
  - Charter Member Ribbon for 30th Anniversary, 1956 (Box 2)